(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T04:37:29.840115",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
憧れてた場所を
The place I longed for
ただ遠くから見ていた
I was just watching from afar
隣に並ぶ夢は
The dream of standing side by side
眩しく煌くダイヤモンド
is a dazzling, sparkling diamond
ポスターにダイス 私らしく光るボイス
Dice on the poster, my uniquely shining voice
聞いて欲しいんだ 大きな夢とメロディ
I want you to hear my big dream and melody
さあ強く強気に
Now, be strong and bold
今サヨナラ
Saying goodbye now
もうくじけない
I won't give up anymore
もっと光る誓うよ
I swear I'll shine even brighter
未来に指切りしてスマイル
Promise to the future with a smile
今更なんてない
There's no such thing as too late
ずっとスマイリング シンキングダンシングオンマイラブ
Always smiling, thinking, dancing on my love
ゆっくりでもいいよ
Even if it's slow, it's okay
でも歩き続けるんだ
But I'll keep on walking
今はまだ真っ白だけど
It's still pure white right now
見てほしい 知ってほしい 今ここに
I want you to see and know me right here
プラチナのポスター 私らしく光るチョイス
A platinum poster, my uniquely shining choice
伝えたいんだ小さなこだわりから
I want to convey my little details
ほらカラフルに
Look, colorfully...
今よろしく
Now, nice to meet you
季節のやつを掴むよ
Catching the seasonal ones
ちょっとジャンプにウィンクをしてもう
With a little jump and a wink
やりすぎなんてない
There's no such thing as too much
もっとグリーミーホッピン フォーマイリトルライフ
More gleamy hopping for my little life
みんな 今日は来てくれてありがとう!
Everyone, thank you for coming today!
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね!
Please enjoy yourselves until the very end!
今日はアイドルの祭りだもっともっと見せちゃいますよ!
Today is Matsuri the idol's day, I'll show you more!
憧れじゃ終わらせない 一歩づつ進んだ
Won't end as just longing, taking steps forward
さあ今バイバイ
Now, bye-bye for now
涙はいらない
No need for tears
明日の笑顔ねがおを 努力にキスをして ヘイ!
Kissing my efforts for tomorrow's smile, hey!
ありえないなんてない
There's no such thing as impossible
もっとグリーミーホッピン フォーマイリトルライフ
More gleamy hopping for my little life
もうあきらめない
I won't give up anymore
昨日へこんでねこんだ 自分と指切りしてスマイル
Making a pinky promise with my depressed past self and smiling
閉じ込めなんてない
There's no locking away
ずっとスマイリング シンキングダンシングオンマイ 愛を込めてずっと歌うよ
Always smiling, thinking, dancing on my... singing with all my love
ありがとうございました! ということで1曲目、S(mile)ING!でした! ありがとうございました!
Thank you very much! That was our first song, S(mile)ING! Thank you very much!
テンション高かった？
Was my excitement high?
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
見てるよ、みんなのこと、ありがとうございます。
I see all of you! Thank you so much.
コメントもたくさん、そしてスーパーチャットもたくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you for all the comments and Super Chats too!
今日のはっしゅたぐは、こちらに映っております、夏色まつり2周年ライブで、たくさんツイートしてください！
Please tweet a lot with today's hashtag shown here!
トレンド入りしたらね、なんか嬉しくなってしまうのでね、目ざしていきましょう！
If it trends, I'll be so happy, so let's aim for that!
それではですね、あの、ちょっと衣装を見てほしいんですよ。
And now, I want you to take a look at my outfit.
なんと、こちらですね、あのノンストップストーリーという、あの、ホロライブみんなでしたライブ、以来ですね、来ました。
You see, this is from the "Non-Stop Story" Hololive all-members live... I'm wearing it since then!
いや、めちゃめちゃかわいいでしょ？ちょっとね、みんなに見てもらいたいものがあって、
Man, isn't it super cute? There's something I want everyone to see,
あの、この後ろ、実はこうなってますよっていうのを見ていただきたかったんですよ。
I wanted you to see how the back actually looks.
見て！この編み込みをしてをもらったの。
Look! They braided my hair for me.
そうなんですよ。そしてこの大きなリボン、こうやってやるとすごい揺れます。
That's right. And this big ribbon, when I move like this, it shakes a lot.
かわいいかろ？かわいいかろ？かわいいかろ？すげえお気に入りなんですよ。
Isn't it cute? It's my absolute favorite.
あとですね、見てほしいのは、このお腹、絶対出してくださいって言ったお腹と、絶対出してくださいって言った肩ですね。
Also, what I want you to see is my stomach—which I insisted they show—and my shoulders.
あと脇... ちょっと恥ずかしいけど、脇とかもね、ちゃんとちょっと見えておりますけども、
And my armpits... It's a bit embarrassing, but you can see my armpits too,
ということでね、衣装はこんな感じでございます。みんなね、それぞれすごいかわいい衣装を着ているんですけども、まつりも負けず劣らずかわいい衣装を着ているので、見せたくなりました。胸が大きい。
So yeah, that's what the outfit looks like. Everyone's wearing super cute outfits, but Matsuri's got a cute one too, so I wanted to show it off. My chest is big.
なんかね、横から見るとね、あんまり... これね、あの正面から見ると、なんか大きいかなって思うんだけど、
You know, seeing it from the side, not so much... From the front, you might think it looks pretty big,
いや、横から見ると、なんかね、思って、あれ？みたいなね、感じがあるんですよね、これね。
but from the side, it's like, "Huh?" you know? It gives that impression.
緊張してる? めちゃめちゃしてるよ。さっき裏返っちゃったもんね。声がね。ちょっと水飲みますね。
Am I nervous? I'm super nervous. My voice cracked earlier, right? Let me drink some water.
あの、みんなに見えるか分からない水がここにあるんですよ。ちょっと飲みます。あ、水こぼしちゃった。
Umm, there's water here that I don't know if you can see. Let me drink some. Ah, I spilled the water.
ということでね、続いていきますか、そろそろ。
So, shall we move on soon?
はーい、ということで、えーと、続いて、はい、行きたいと思います。アイドルらしく歌いますよ。
Right then, um, next up, yes, I'd like to go on. I'll sing it like an idol.
続いての、とってもとっても可愛い曲なので、えっと、にゃんにゃんしてくれると嬉しいです。
The next song is super, super cute, so I'd be happy if you'd "nya-nya" along with it.
それでは、聴いてください。おねだり Shall We~?
Without further ado, please listen to: "Onedari Shall We~?"
いたずら目して thank you
With a mischievous look, thank you
鈴が響いて bye-bye
A bell rings out, bye-bye
街灯に照らされて また明日…なんて甘い 子猫じゃないのよ
Illuminated by streetlights, until tomorrow... or so sweetly. I'm no kitten,
にゃお！にゃお！にゃお！にゃお！
Meow! Meow! Meow! Meow!
触れてよ ねぇ
Touch me, hey
やさしく ねぇ
Gently, hey
指絡めて 背伸びをして 瞳閉じて silence
Intertwine your fingers, stand on your toes, close your eyes, silence
風が頬を撫でて 香る くゆくゆく
The wind caresses my cheek, fragrant, swaying gently
今夜のおかずは ハンバーグかな
Tonight's side dish might be a hamburger
そうじゃない！
That's not it!
いたずら目して やだもん
With a mischievous look, no way
ご褒美が 欲しいもん
I want a reward
まつ毛が 触れるほど 超接近
So close our eyelashes almost touch
なんて甘い 時々 したでしょ にゃお！
How sweet, ever so often, right? Meow!
ちょっとして何？
What do you mean?
意地悪がないの
Aren't you being teasing?
逃げちゃうから 捕まえてみて 裏の路地に come on 満月 照らす おさんぽ道 ひょいひょいひょい
Since I'll run away, try catching me to the back alley, come on. Full moon illuminates our stroll path, hyoi hyoi hyoi.
さあおいで 秘密のステージへ shall we dance?
Now come along to the secret stage, shall we dance?
零いた！
Found you!
にゃんにゃん...
Nyan nyan...
にゃあ
Nyaa
いたずら目して thank you
With a mischievous look, thank you.
鈴が響いて bye-bye
Bells echoing, bye-bye.
街灯に照らされた
Illuminated by streetlights,
また明日
see you tomorrow.
…な～んて甘い
...or so sweetly it goes.
子猫じゃないのよ にゃお！
I'm not a kitten, nyao!
もう時間は 残りわずか
With time running out,
しゃららん
shararan,
最後にひとつ お願いあるの
I have one final request.
すりすり くるくる
Snuggling and spinning,
甘えんぼう
acting spoiled.
手と手合わせて happy
Hands together, happy!
目と目合わせて wink
Eyes together, wink!
輝く王子様 魔法を解いて
Radiant prince, break the spell.
心音が響く
Where heartbeats echo,
瞳を閉じてね
close your eyes.
勇気を出していいよ
You can gather your courage.
ざわめく街が 息を潜む
The bustling city holds its breath,
すっきり
completely.
なんか思い出
Feeling a bit sentimental,
ドキドキしたでしょ？
my heart was pounding, right?
にゃお！
Nyao!
子猫じゃないのよ
I'm not a kitten, you know!
はーい、ありがとうございます！
Haai, thank you very much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
もうドキドキしましたけども、どうでしたか？
My heart was pounding so much, how was it?
猫に乗れました？
Did you ride the cat?
にゃあ、にゃあしておりましたかね？
Did I go nyaa, nyaa?
すごい緊張したよ！
I was so nervous!
なんとですね、これあのね、本当にライブ映像をね、
And you know what, truly, for the live footage,
スマイリングもそうだし、おねだりShall Weもそうなんですけど、
both for Smiling and Onedari Shall We,
ライブ映像をね、あの、見ながらね、
while watching the live video,
こうやって練習したんですよ。
I practiced like this over and over.
ね、どうですか？
So, how was it?
可愛かったかな？
Was it cute?
もしね、あのプロデューサーさんたちがいらっしゃったらね、
If any of the producers were here,
「あ、この振り付けは！」ってなってくれたんじゃないかなと
I think they'd be like, "Oh, this choreography!"
思います。
you know.
とっても可愛いですよね。
It's super cute, isn't it?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
アイドルって思って貰えてますかね？
Do you think of me as an idol?
どうかな？どうかな？
I wonder, I wonder?
あ、じゃあ改めてなんですけど、
Oh, and to reiterate,
皆さんともう一度やりたいことがありまして、
there's something I want to do with everyone once more.
あの、まつりが「こんばんはー！」って言ったら、
When Matsuri says, "Good evening!",
みんなも「こんばんはー！」ってコメントしてくれたり、
will everyone comment or shout out
声をだしてくれたりしますか？
"Good evening!" too?
いいかな？
Is that alright?
まつりが「こんばんはー！」って言ったら
When Matsuri says "Good evening!"
「こんばんはー！」だよ。
you reply "Good evening!".
いいですか？
Got it?
いきますよ？
Here we go?
せーの、こんばんはー！
Ready, set... Good evening!
ありがとーー！
Thank yooou!
すごい！サイリウムめちゃめちゃ綺麗ですね！
Amazing! The glow sticks look so beautiful!
すっけ綺麗だ！
So breathtakingly pretty!
ありがとうございます、たくさんね、宣言をいただきましてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for sending in so many declarations.
ということでですね、あの、ちょっと早いんですけどもね、
And with that, although it's a bit early,
続いての曲はね、ちょっと思い出があるからね、
for the next song, I have some fond memories
語りたい感もあるんですよ。
so I kind of want to talk about it.
続いての曲はですね、たぶん、そのまつりをちょっと前から知ってくださって、
As for the next song, if you've known about Matsuri from a little while ago,
でも一昨年とか知ってたらね、知ってくれてるんじゃないかなって思うんですけど、
or if you knew about her two years ago, I think you'd probably know it.
まあね、最近知ったよって方もね、まつりちゃんぽいかな？みたいなね、
Well, for those who just recently got to know me, there's a song that feels very "Matsuri-like",
曲があるんですよ、一つね。
you know, just one.
それでおね、なんと今日はね、こんな感じのね、こんな感じの衣装なのでね、
And so, since today I'm wearing an outfit just like this,
あの、まあ、歌ったら、可愛いって思ってもらえるかなっていうのがあって、
once I sing it, I wonder if you'll think, "Oh, how cute."
あとね、この曲の後もね、他のおっかのなんか、ね、いらっしゃるのでね、そちらもお楽しみにしてほしいんですけども。
Also, after this song, there'll be others appearing too, so I hope you look forward to that as well.
はい、動きが可愛い。あ、本当ですか？
Yes, my movements are cute. Ah, really?
今日アイドルできてますか？
Am I being an idol today?
なんか、あそう、あの、今日はね、スクショをね、たくさん撮っていただいて、
Oh right, today I'd be so happy if you took lots of screenshots
こちらのハッシュタグをね、上ですね、こちらのハッシュタグをいっぱいつけてツイートしてくれたら嬉しいですよ！
and tweeted them with this hashtag right up here!
お願いいたしまーす！
Please do!
めちゃめちゃアイドルできてる？
Am I doing a great idol job?
あ、本当？てれちゃうね、てれちゃうね、
Ah, really? I get all shy.
なんか最近、最近ってほどでもないけど、ずっと、いやまつりちゃんは、まつりちゃんだけはアイドルじゃないでしょってよく言われるのでね、
Lately—well, not really "lately"—people always say, "Matsuri-chan, you're the only one who isn't an idol, right?"
本日はね、あのアイドルらしいとこを見せれたら嬉しいなと思うところで、
So today, I'd be so happy if I could show off my idol-like side.
あとですね、あの、今更な、今更なのかわかんないですけど、
And also, I don't know if this is belated or not,
2周年を迎えまして...
celebrating our 2nd anniversary...
はい。おめでとうという言葉をかけてあげてください。
Please say "congratulations" to us,
まつりも含め。おねがいします。
including Matsuri too. Please!
ライブだい…今日も無料やっております。歌枠のときとかもね、いつもありがとうございます。
Today's live is... also free as always. Thank you as always for the song streams and everything.
本日も無料やっておりますので、楽しんでいって下さい最後まで。
Today is also free, so please enjoy it to the very end!
ということでですね、続いての曲行く前に水を飲みます。水を飲ませていただきますね、失礼いたします。
So with that said, before going to the next song, I'll have a sip of water. Let me drink some water, excuse me.
じゃあ、行きました。マシュマポもありがとね、入ってくれて。
Okay, I'm back. Thanks for joining us, Marshimapo!
それじゃあ、行ってみましょう。
Well then, let's give it a try.
ファンサ！
Fansa!
好きになって！もっと！ 私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "with a loving flying kiss"!
気のせいじゃない目であってよ
Look at me with eyes that aren't just your imagination,
ハート作って恋しちゃってください
make a heart and fall in love!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って 恋しちゃってください
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
やれること なんでもします N.G.なしで
I'll do whatever it takes, with no restrictions,
ダイヤサリ女性
throwing myself into it with all my might!
エゴサで見つけた アンチのコメ
Found your anti-comments through egosurfing,
ふざけんな 誰よりわかってるし でも大丈夫 ここに立てばみんながいる
but it's okay, when I stand here, everyone is here!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me more!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで” トリコにする
My repayment is "with a loving flying kiss" to capture your heart!
夢を miseru！もっと！
Showing you my dreams more!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoying this loving special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にする
I'll read them over and over as my treasures.
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
It's still too early for scandals,
裏切りません
but I won't betray you!
宣言します
I declare that!
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment!
ふざけんな 実力で勝ってやる
Damn it, I'll win with pure skill!
だから辞めない 負けず嫌い私はいる
That's why I won't quit, I'm a sore loser and I'm right here!
拳上げた！もっと！
Fists raised higher!
汗をかいて！もっと！
Sweating more!
恩返しは 愛のこもったマツリビームで 大歓声！
My repayment is with a loving Matsuri Beam and a huge cheer!
まだまだねぇ？もっと受け止めてね
Still want more? Receive it all,
愛のこもったわがままソング ファンサしちゃうぞ
this loving, selfish song, I'll give you fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is near, how lonely.
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も次もまた会えるよね？
We'll meet again next time and the time after, right?
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Even words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
even words from someone heartless—
必要なんだ強くなろう
they're all necessary, let's get stronger!
好きに叫ぶ！もっと！
Shout out what you love more!
楽しんじゃお！もっと！
Enjoy yourself more!
忘れないで特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, let's make this a special day!
ともに歌おう！もっと！
Let's sing together more!
ともに歩もう！もっと！
Let's walk together more!
愛言葉はとびっきりの l-o-v-e！
Our love word is a dazzling l-o-v-e!
好きになって！もっと！ 私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "with a loving flying kiss"!
好きになって！もっと！ 私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "with a loving flying kiss"!
好きになって！もっと！ 私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "with a loving flying kiss"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということでですね、あの、皆さん、ちょっと息切れがやばいんですけども、
So everyone... I'm getting really out of breath, but...
ありがとうございました。
thank you so much.
それでは、ちょっとね、あの、スペシャルなゲストをね、呼んでいきたいと思いますので、
Now then, I'd like to invite a special guest to join us, so...
いいでございましょうか？
is that alright with you all?
皆さんありがとうございます。ちょっと泣きそうになってますけどもね、
Thank you everyone. I'm almost about to cry, but...
ちょっとここでね、この泣きそうな祭りに変わってじゃないんですけど、一緒に歌って下さるスペシャルなゲストを呼んでいきたいと思います。
instead of this tearful Matsuri here, I'd like to invite a special guest who will sing together with me.
それでは、ちょっと待ってくださいね。あのね、祭り本当に緊張して、
So please wait just a moment. You know, Matsuri was really nervous...
一人じゃできないと思って、すごいずっと呼びたかった子がいたので、あの、呼ばせていただいたんですけども。
and thinking she couldn't do it alone, there was someone she really wanted to call out to, so she invited them.
いや、誰だろうな？なんかこう、
I wonder who it could be? Someone sort of like...
こういう感じの、なんかこう、こういう感じの子が来そうな気がするんですけどもね。
I have a feeling someone with this kind of vibe might show up.
はい、皆さん、あの、ありがとうございます。ファンサマジで声震えすぎて、
Yes, everyone, um, thank you so much. My voice was shaking so much during "Fan Service"...
あの、ブルブルだったけど、気持ちは込めたのでね、また見直して下さると嬉しいなと思います。
it was all wobbling, but I poured my feelings into it, so I hope you'll re-watch it.
ということで、そろそろ、
And with that, shall we soon...
呼んでいきましょうか？
invite them out?
本日のスペシャルゲストはこの方です！どうぞ！
Today's special guest is this person! Here they are!
あ、すいちゃん！
Ah, Suichan!
イェーイ！
Yay!
来た来た来た来た！うわ、
They're here, they're here! Wow...
水星の如く現れた星の彗星、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
Appearing like a shooting star, the comet of the stars, idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
来てくれましたよー！祭り、ちょっと、あの、裏で ちょっと泣きそうな。
She came! Matsuri was, um, backstage almost crying...
本当にね、祭りもね、あのね、緊張もそうなんだけど、
Really, Matsuri too, um, not just from nervousness, but...
いろんな思いがこうみ上げてね、泣きそうになってしまう。
all sorts of feelings welled up, and she ended up almost crying.
いや、もうね、私はもうすっかりリハも一緒だったから、すいちゃん見てたんだけど、すいちゃんは本当に頑張ってたし、リハでまずずっと緊張する、すいちゃん、
Well, I had been through rehearsals together with her, so I was watching Suichan, and she worked really hard. Even during rehearsals, Suichan was so nervous...
「大丈夫大丈夫！大丈夫だから！もう大丈夫大丈夫、ぜんぜんもうみんなも許してくれる、間違えたってみたいな、そういう感じだったから。
I was telling her, "It's okay, it's okay! It'll be fine! Everyone will totally forgive you even if you make a mistake," things like that.
なんかもう、そう、泣きそうだよね。しかもね、今日はね、すいすいもアイドル一緒なんですよ。
So yeah, I felt like crying too. Plus, today, Suisui is an idol together with us.
そうなんです、言うの忘れとました。
That's right, I forgot to mention it!
祭りちゃんに被っちゃって、そう、私もね、久しぶりにこんな衣装、ちょっと祭りちゃんと一緒にお揃いで。さ、お揃いなんです。
It overlapped with Matsuri-chan—yeah, and for the first time in a while, I'm wearing an outfit matching Matsuri-chan. Yes, we match!
どうですか？
How is it?
いいですか？
Good?
今撮影タイムですよ。
It's photo time right now, you know.
皆さん、どうですか？
Everyone, how is it?
一緒に撮ってくださいね。
Please take pictures together, okay?
かわいいですか？
Are we cute?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
イェーイ！
Yay!
イェイイェイイェイ！
Yay, yay, yay!
いいでしょー？
Pretty good, right?
いいでしょ？ありがとう呼んでくれて。
Right? Thanks for inviting me.
いや、あのね、このね、呼んだのには理由があってですね、
Well, you know, there's a reason why I called her here...
あのですね、なんと、すいすいがやってたじゃないですか、すいすいもライブをね。
um, Suisui was holding a live stream too, wasn't she?
やっておりました。
I was!
それを見て祭りは感動して、本当に感動して、祭りもやりたい！そうそうそう、ずっと思ってた。
Seeing that, Matsuri was moved, truly moved, and thought, "I want to do that too!" Yes, I kept thinking that.
そう、だから本当に、すいすいは仲間であり、その祭りの尊敬できる人なんですよ。ファンとしても本当に好きだし、なんかこう、同じそのホロライブとしての、この尊敬できる相手だなっていうのですごい大好きだから、ま、その配信を見て、祭りもうれしいなって思ったし、同じ舞台に立ちたいなって。
Yeah, so Suisui is truly a comrade, and someone Matsuri respects. I genuinely love her as a fan, and since she's someone I respect within Hololife, I love her so much. Watching that stream made me happy, and I thought I wanted to stand on the same stage.
うん！実はね、私の誕生日のライブに祭りちゃんをちょっと、オファーというか、あの、してたんだけど、あの、残念ながら、予定が合わなくて、
Yeah! Actually, for my birthday live, I made an offer to Matsuri-chan, but unfortunately, our schedules didn't line up...
呼ばなくて、で、それで今日はね、
so she couldn't come. And so today,
あの、代わりにじゃないけど、あの、呼んでくれて、で、やっと二人で、ね、やりたかったぞ！って
instead, she invited me, and we finally got to do this together! That's what I wanted to say!
そうなんです！やったじゃん！
That's right! We finally did it!
そうなんです！
Indeed!
てぃてぃ！てぃてぃ！てぃてぃ！よっしゃよっしゃよっしゃよっしゃ！
Teetee! Teetee! Teetee! Let's go, let's go!
そしてね、本日歌う曲なんですけども、
And now, as for the song we're singing today...
ちょっと曲名を言いつつですね、あの、これ、実はね、歌ったことあるんですよ、二人で。
while mentioning the title... actually, the two of us have sung this before.
あるよね？うん。
Right? Yeah.
あの、告知とか、なんかして。
Um, make an announcement or something.
この流れでね、なんか、二人だけで歌った機械があって、
In this flow... we had an opportunity to sing just the two of us,
え、どこで歌ったんだろな？
Eh, where did we sing it?
文化放送超A&G+毎週日曜日11時から行われている、ホロライブプレゼント星街すいせいのミュージック・スペースかな？かな？
Could it be on Nippon Cultural Broadcasting's "Cho A&G+", every Sunday from 11 AM, "Hololife Presents Hoshimachi Suisei's Music Space"? Could it?
そうだったかな？そうだったかな？
Was it? Was it?
答え合わせはね、すいすいね、あれ残ってますよね、たしかに。
For the answer check, Suisui, that archive is still up, right?
あ、そう、アーカイブがね、私のチャンネルには残ってるのでね。
Ah, yes, the archive is still on my channel, so...
うん、ちょっとね、それを確認してくれない人は勘違いだな！勘違いな！
Yeah, anyone who hasn't checked that is mistaken! Mistaken!
ということでね、もうこの分かりやすい宣伝を挟んだところでね、早速歌っていきたいなと思いますよ。
And with that, after inserting that obvious advertisement, we'd like to get right into singing it!
それでは、いいですか？準備は。
So, are you ready? Are you prepared?
めちゃめちゃドキドキする一緒にね。
My heart is pounding so much singing together.
ターの好きなものなので、
It's one of my favorites, so...
うん！
Yeah!
楽しんで歌っていきましょう！
Let's enjoy singing it together!
おっしゃー！
Let's do this!
はい！
Yes!
行きますよ、それでは聞いてください。「君の知らない物語」。
Here we go. Please listen to: "Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari".
いつもの通りのある日の事
Like always, on that day,
君は突然立ち上がり言った
you suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜 星を見に行こう」
“Tonight, let's go stargazing!”
夜空は星が降るようで
The night sky looked like it would drop the stars!
いつからだろう 君のことを
Since when, I wonder,
追いかける私がいた
have I been chasing after you?
どうかお願い
Please, please,
驚かないで聞いてよ
don't be surprised, listen
私のこの想いをお
to these feelings of mine.
君は指す夏の大三角
You point at the summer triangle,
覚えて空を見る
and remembering, I look at the sky.
楽しげなひとつ隣の君
While you enjoy yourself right next to me...
本当はずっと君のことを
The truth is, all along,
どこかでわかっていた
I knew it somewhere inside.
見つかったって届きはしない
Even if I found it, it won't reach you...
ダメだよ 泣かないで
No, don't cry,
そう言い聞かせた
I told myself.
強がる私は怯懦で
I acted tough, but cowardly,
興味がないようなふりをしてた
acting like I didn't care at all.
だけど 胸を刺す痛みは増えてく
Yet the pain stabbing my heart only grew.
ああそうか 好きになるってこういうことなんだね
Ah, I see... so this is what it means to fall in love.
どうしたい? 言ってごらん
“What's wrong? Tell me,”
心の中の声がする
my inner voice says.
君の隣がいい
I want to be by your side,
真実(こたえ)は残酷だ
but the truth is so cruel.
言わなかった 言えなかった
I didn't say it, I couldn't say it,
二度と戻れない
and now I can never go back.
あの夏の日の きらめく星
Those glittering stars on that summer day,
今でも思い出せるよ
I can still remember them.
笑った顔も 怒った顔も
Your smiling face, your angry face,
大好きでした
I loved them all.
おかしいよね わかっていたのに
It's funny, isn't it? Even though I knew...
君の知らない 私だけの秘密
It's a secret known only to me, unknown to you.
夜を越えて 遠い思い出の君が
Crossing the night, you from distant memories
指をさす 無邪気な声で
point your finger with such an innocent voice.
君の隣が
By your side...
真実(こたえ)は残酷だ
The truth is so cruel.
いつもどおりのある日の事
That day was the same as any other,
君は突然立ち上がり言った
you suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight."
「たまにはいいこと言うんだね」
"You come up with something good every now and then."
なんてみんなして言って笑った
That's what everyone said as they laughed.
明かりもない道を
On a path with no light,
バカみたいにはしゃいで歩いた
we frolicked and walked like fools.
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に
So that we wouldn't be crushed
押し潰されないように
by the loneliness and anxiety we carried,
真っ暗な世界から見上げた
we looked up from a pitch-black world,
夜空は星が降るようで
and the night sky seemed to rain stars.
いつからだろう 君の事を
I wonder when it was that I began
追いかける私がいた
chasing after you.
どうか お願い
Please, I beg you,
驚かないで聞いてよ
listen without being surprised
私のこの想い
to these feelings of mine.
どうでしたでしょうか？
How was our performance?
どうだったでしょうか 君シラでし...
How was it? It was KimiSira...
君シラ良い曲だね
KimiSira is such a good song!
もう これで歌うのすごく難しくって
Man, singing this was super difficult,
本当にこう もう500回練習しました リハで。もうギリギリまでね やってましたのね。
We literally practiced it 500 times in rehearsal, right up until the very edge!
いやでもすごく楽しかったですね 本当にありがとうございます
Yeah, but it was a lot of fun. Thank you so much!
いやこちらこそ本当にお呼びいただきまして 本当にありがとうございます ああ
No, thank you so much for inviting us! Thank you!
またね 何かの機会に 今度は私のライブにまた呼びたいから
Next time, I want to invite you to my live stream too!
呼んでほしいよ また一緒に歌おう ね
I'd love that! Let's sing together again.
衣装もね その衣装もすごく可愛いから ちょっとちょっとターンしてよ
Your outfit is so cute, too. Do a little turn!
いいよ
Okay.
えー可愛いね
Aww, so cute!
じゃあお揃いだからね このね リボンもおそろいおそろいのりぼん
It's matching! The ribbons are matching.
おそろい おそろい おそろい なリボン あ、可愛い
Matching, matching, matching ribbons! Ah, cute!
可愛いですよ どうですか 可愛いってこれは高評価！ありがとう
It's so cute! What do you think? "So cute"—that's a high rating! Thank you!
サイドテールもお揃いなのだよね。あ、そうそうそう。実はね、実はね可愛い、キュン点が多いですね。
Our side tails match, too. Ah, that's right! Actually, it's super cute—lots of doki-doki points.
と いうことで すしすし 本当に 本日はありがとうございました
So, Sushi-Sushi, thank you so much for today!
ありがとう！これからも頑張ってください 夏色まつりさん
Thank you! Keep up the good work, Natsuiro Matsuri-san!
ありがとうございます。3年目ももう頑張っていきたいと思いますので！
Thank you! I'll keep working hard in my 3rd year too!
いやもうね本当にね今日こうして迎えられたのはね
Truly, being able to welcome this day...
すしすし含めね まあいろんなホロライブメンバーのおかげですよ 本当にね盛り上げてくれてありがとうございました
Including Sushi-Sushi, thanks to all the Hololive members who hyped us up, thank you so much!
私たちは一期生の皆さんがいたからこそ 今まで繋いでくださって
We wouldn't be here if not for the 1st gen members connecting us up to now!
そうそう 本当に今こうやっていろんな舞台立たせていただけてます 本当にありがとうございます よろしくね
That's right! Thank you so much for letting us stand on all these stages. Please treat us well!
大好きだよ 大好きだよ
I love you! I love you!
恥ずかしいわ 恥ずかしいわ
So embarrassing! So embarrassing!
ということで ですね じゃあそろそろ はい お別れということで すしすしお見送りしていこうか
So, it's almost time to say goodbye. Let's see Sushi-Sushi off!
どうぞ お見送り！ ありがとう！バイバイ またね
Go ahead, send her off! Thank you! Bye-bye, see you!
バイバイ またね
Bye-bye, see you!
ありがとう！ やりがいですね本当にね
Thank you! I'm so grateful, truly.
ということでですね あの すしすしが来ててくださいました スペシャルゲストはすしすしだったんですよね
So, Sushi-Sushi came as our special guest today!
いやー この配信が始まるまでのわかんなかったんですよね もう まさかまさかのビッグゲストでございましたけどもね
We didn't even know until the stream started! What a massive surprise guest.
いやもうね 本当に嬉しいね なんか 本当にすしすし大好きで すしすがいなくなった
I'm so happy. I really love Sushi-Sushi, and even though Sushi-Sushi is gone...
今も話すけど 本当になんかこう友達としても好きだし そのホロライブメンバーの仲間としても好きだし あの あのね ファンとしてもね 好きなんですよ 本当に大好き
...I'm still talking about her. I love her as a friend, as a Hololive member, and as a fan. I truly love her so much!
だからね これからも仲良くできたらなと思っております はい ということでですね
So I hope we can keep getting along well. Yes! So,
今3分でございますけど なんとですね あの もうね最後の曲になりました
it's been 30 minutes, and guess what? It's time for our final song!
はい あのね この曲はですね まつりが初めてのね誕生日のときにですね ファンの方がくれたプレゼントの曲なんですでございますよ
This song is a present given to Matsuri by fans on her very first birthday!
はい そしてですね 今から歌う曲 まぁ言ってしまえばオリジナル曲になるのかな? まつりイメージのオリジナル曲になっております
And the song we're about to sing is, you could say, an original song for Matsuri!
そして あの なんと この後22時15分からですね
And what's more, starting at 22:15 tonight,
今から歌う曲の歌ってみたが上がります！
the cover of the song we're about to sing will be released!
これね びっくりでしょ？
Surprising, right?
そう ずっと出したかったんだけど ちょっといつ出そうっかな どうしようっかなって出し惜しみしてたらね
I've wanted to release it for a long time, but kept holding back wondering when and how to release it...
曲を作ってもらってからもう約2年経っておりますよ。
It's been about two years since they made this song for me.
約2年、まだ2年経ってないけどね。
About two years, well not quite two years yet,
大体2年くらい経っております。
roughly two years have passed.
あの作って下さったファンの方も本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much to the fans who created it for me.
それではですね、ちょっと水を飲んでからいこうかな
Well then, I think I'll drink some water first
気合を入れてね。
and get pumped up.
すげえさ、歌うのね緊張するし難しいので
Singing in front of everyone is so nerve-wracking and difficult,
頑張りますね、水飲みます。
so I'll do my best. I'm going to drink some water.
えーということで、皆さん続いてが最後の曲です。
And with that, everyone, the next song is our final one.
緊張する。
I'm so nervous.
聞いてください。
Please listen to it.
君と眺める夏の花
Summer Flowers We View Together
もっともっと上がるよ 空に大きな夏の花
Reaching higher and higher into the sky, large summer flowers bloom
君と眺める夏の花
作詞：芳賀雄 作曲：メリッサ
[Song: Summer Flowers We View Together
Lyrics: Yu Haga / Music: Melissa]
フーラフラ歩くよ 楽しい香りに誘われて
Strolling along aimlessly, lured by the delightful aroma
カーラコロ響くよ 下駄の音 どこまでも
The sound of geta clogs echoes on and on
キーラキラ輝く 屋台の明かりに飛び込んで
Diving into the sparkling lights of the food stalls
ピカピカ頬張る 真っ赤な苺飴
Happily munching on a bright red candy-coated strawberry
さぁどーんとはーっとね ずっと待ってた！
With a big bang and a hearty cheer, I've been waiting all this time!
「ほらね、今年も花火が打ちあがる」
"Look, this year's fireworks are shooting up again!"
さぁ！祭りだ祭りだ祭りだ わっしょい！
Now! Festival, festival, festival, wasshoi!
1,2,3の で声出して！
Shout out on 1, 2, 3!
手と手をつないで 叫ぼうよ わっしょい！
Holding hands, let's shout, wasshoi!
まーだまだ上がるよ 今夜の花火もテンションも
Still climbing higher and higher, tonight's fireworks and our excitement too!
ガヤガヤ賑やか 見るもの全てが眩しくて
Bustling and lively, everything I see is so dazzling
シャクシャク溶けかけ 頬張る かき氷
Crunching on a melting, shaved ice treat
さぁ、ぱんばか馬鹿やって クスクス笑わせて
Now, acting a bit foolish and making each other giggle
「君の、笑顔の花火が打ち上がる」
"Your smiling fireworks are bursting into bloom!"
さぁ楽しい祭だ 止まるな わっしょい！ 弾けるリズムは最後まで
Now, the fun festival won't stop, wasshoi! Keep the rhythm going till the end
浴衣も忘れて 跳ねるよ わっしょい！
Forgetting our yukatas, let's jump, wasshoi!
もっともっと上がるよ 空に大きな夏の花
Reaching higher and higher into the sky, large summer flowers bloom
本当に2周年ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for the 2nd anniversary!
3周年でももう全力で駆けつけてついてこい今夜も回ろう！
Even for the 3rd anniversary, I'll charge forward, keep up and let's go around tonight!
わたあめ頬張り 溶けるよ一瞬 輝く時間もとけていく
Munching on cotton candy, melting instantly, shining moments fade away
君との思い出 溶けない一生 消えない宝物
Memories with you will never melt—an eternal, unforgettable treasure
祭りだ祭りだ祭りだ わっしょい！流れる光に照らされて
Festival, festival, festival, wasshoi! Illuminated by the flowing lights
全てが眩しい思い出 わっしょい！
Everything is a dazzling memory, wasshoi!
もっともっと輝け 君と眺める夏の花
Shine brighter and brighter, summer flowers we view together
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
それじゃあいきますよ！せーの！お祭りわっしょい！
Well then, here we go! Ready, set! Festival wasshoi!
これからもよろしくね！愛してるぞ！
Please keep supporting me from now on! I love you all!